signupgenius.com 2019-06-24

# Privacy Policy

 About Us / Privacy Policy 

###  Last Updated: May 25, 2018

Let’s face it. You came to this page because you are concerned about your privacy. You don’t know us and honestly… you just don’t trust us. Are we right? That’s perfectly understandable. There are a lot of fraudulent sites on the internet.We started this company to help churches, temples, schools, soccer moms, coaches, room parents and people just like us organize their lives. We want to be a company with integrity that will simplify life for our users, not take advantage them. So if any of the items below are unclear or you have further questions, please contact us.

SignUpGenius  
13777 Ballantyne Corporate Pl  
Suite 500  
Charlotte, NC 28277

##   
Our Policy:

**We do not knowingly add users to our website without permission.**  A person can be added to our site when they register themselves to create a sign up form (a “Creator”) or when someone invites them to a sign up form (a “Participant”). A Creator will provide certain information to us (e.g., name, email address, etc.) and will create a password. A Participant will provide his or her name plus any additional information that the Creator of that sign up page requests from each Participant. SignUpGenius does not and cannot control how the Creators of a sign up use the information you provide as a Participant. If a Creator adds your information to our site and you do not want to be a part of our service, [contact us](https://www.signupgenius.com/help) and our staff will delete you from our system.

**How do we use and share your information?** We use the information we collect for a number of purposes, including to improve our website’s functionality, improve the services, communicate with users, and for internal business analysis or other business purposes. Your personal information is provided by you (or a Creator) as part of the sign up application and is available to the Creators of the sign ups you are involved in. We do not display your contact information publicly on our site or disclose personally identifiable information to third parties, except for when (1) we have your permission to make the disclosure, (2) the disclosure is necessary for the purpose for which the information was obtained, (3) a third party is assisting us to provide or manage the services or website, or (4) where otherwise stated in this policy. We also may disclose information where permitted by applicable law or when the disclosure is necessary, in our sole discretion, for the establishment or maintenance of legal claims or legal compliance, to satisfy any law, regulation, subpoena or government request, or in connection with litigation.

In the event we are acquired by or merged or consolidated into another entity, or if there is a sale of our assets, your information may be transferred to the entity acquiring us or our assets or the entity that survives the merger or consolidation. You acknowledge and agree that in the foregoing circumstances, your information may be disclosed to such third party.

**We will try not to bother you with unwanted emails.** You will, of course, receive emails as part of the SignUpGenius services including, but not limited to, invites to sign up forms, status updates, and reminder notifications. In addition, we have email newsletters and other marketing/promotional materials that we send out periodically. You can unsubscribe from communications that are not specifically related to sign ups you are connected to by clicking on the “Unsubscribe” link or by following the instructions provided in those communications. If you do not wish to receive any email communications from SignUpGenius, you may [contact us](https://www.signupgenius.com/help), and our staff will delete you from our system.

Please see the “Cookies” section under technical details below for additional information regarding cookies that we use to provide you with our services.

**We give the creator of the sign up choices about the privacy of his/her sign up form and what data he/she will collect.** We offer multiple security settings that the Creator can choose to determine who can see a sign up page, who can sign up on the page, and what information is required to sign up for something. We let the Creator make these choices. SignUpGenius does not require contact information from Participants in order for them to participate on a sign up; however, we do give the Creator the ability to require certain contact information. The type of data collected from a Participant may include:

Requested Data

| 

Is Required by SignUpGenius

| 

Can be required by the Creator

| 

Can be viewed publicly on internet    
  
---|---|---|---  
  
Name

| 

Yes

| 

Yes

| 

Optional  
(Creator decides)  
  
Email

| 

No

| 

Yes

| 

No  
  
Phone

| 

No

| 

Yes

| 

No  
  
Address

| 

No

| 

Yes

| 

No  
  
Creating a SignUpGenius Account

| 

No

| 

Yes

| 

No  
  
Custom Questions

| 

No

| 

Yes

| 

No  
  
We do not publicly promote or link the web addresses of the sign ups on our site without approval of the Creator to try to ensure that only the people to which you promote your sign up will see it. The Creator has the option to promote the sign up page publicly or to a select group of people.

**To make logging into SignUpGenius easier, users have the option to sign up and log in using their Facebook account.** When you sign in using Facebook, SignUpGenius may receive the following information: your public profile, friend list, and email address. SignUpGenius uses this information to authenticate your identity and link your Facebook profile information to your SignUpGenius account. Facebook gives you the option to post information about your sign up activities from our website to your Facebook profile page to share with others within your network. SignUpGenius will only use the information collected in accordance with this policy.

**Our employees have access to your account data when needed to help provide the services of our site.** Our employees may view your personal account data for a number of reasons, including to help solve a problem that you or another user is having with any part of our service, answer any questions that you may have regarding our service or website, and for internal business analysis to improve our service as well as your user experience.

**Our site collects anonymous aggregate data and may choose to make some of this data public.** Our site gathers anonymous aggregated data like web statistics and demographics statistics on our users. This data may be used to help us run our business, attract advertisers/investors, and measure the effectiveness of our marketing efforts. We may choose to share or publicize certain anonymous aggregated data about our site. However, because this data is anonymous and in summary form (e.g., does not include your name, email address, home address, etc.), no advertisers or third parties receive this private information about you. For details about the aggregate data, see the "Web Analytics" section in the technical details at the bottom of this page.

**For our online advertisements, we do our best to avoid inappropriate or offensive ads.  **Advertising that you see on our site comes from various sources. An advertisement could be from a company that we partnered with directly. Alternatively, an advertisement could be provided to us by an advertising network that programmatically fills the ad slot, including but not limited to Google's DoubleClick Ad Exchange or Google Adsense, to automatically fill our advertising inventory. For ads that are provided programmatically, we do attempt to filter out sensitive or controversial categories where possible through our account settings. While we do not manually preview every ad before it is served, we periodically monitor the advertising and block any advertisement that we deem offensive or inappropriate. We are in no way responsible for the content of an advertiser's website if you choose to click on an advertisement. We also offer the ability to remove advertisements from your sign ups with a  [paid subscription](https://www.signupgenius.com/pricing) for those who prefer it. 

**We allow and may assist third-party ad networks or vendors in collecting non-personally identifiable information (non-PII) in order to serve relevant advertising both on our site and elsewhere.** Like many web sites, we partner with ad networks that utilize contextual marketing, which is targeted advertising based on user data, such as web behavior. Ads on our site or in our emails may utilize data collected on other sites. Conversely, data collected on our site or via our emails may impact ads seen on other sites. Information gathered is generally used for geo-targeting purposes (showing New York real estate ads to someone in New York, for example) or showing certain ads based on specific sites visited (such as showing cooking ads to someone who frequents cooking sites). For the technical details related to contextual marketing and opt-out information, please see the "Third-Party Ad Networks" section below.

**Our staff periodically reviews site data for the purpose of developing a better service for our users.  **Our employees, contractors, or vendors can review all data on our site for the purpose of helping us improve the services. For example, we review what themes people are using and the titles of created sign ups so that we can see which events and holidays people find the site useful for. We may periodically view individual sign up forms on our site so that we can understand how people are using the services.

**We take precautions, but cannot provide guarantees.** We do our best to secure your data through the programming of our services and the use of security measures that we deem appropriate for the type of data provided. However, we cannot completely guarantee that no part of our system or site will ever fail or be compromised. If you ever suspect that our site or services has contributed to your personal information being compromised, please  [contact us](https://www.signupgenius.com/help) immediately so that we can investigate and try to resolve the matter.

##   
Technical Details:

**SignUpGenius  Cookies**  
A cookie is a small amount of data, which often includes an anonymous unique identifier, that is sent to your browser from a web site's servers and stored on your computer's hard drive. Cookies are required for the SignUpGenius service. We use cookies to track and record user session information. Some examples include keeping you logged into your account while keeping your session secure, views of specific pages or modals, and the number of password reset requests. We do not use permanent cookies but will require users to log in periodically to our site in order to help protect your account information.      

**Log Files**  
Like many other web sites, SignUpGenius.com makes use of log files. The information inside the log files includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, type of browser, Internet Service Provider (ISP), date/time stamp, referring/exit pages, and number of clicks to analyze trends, administer the site, track user's movement around the site, and gather demographic information.

**Web Analytics**  
In addition to our own programming, we use web analysis services, such as Google Analytics, to compile aggregated statistics. Web analytics services utilize the data collected to track and examine the use of our site, to prepare reports on its activities and share them with other services. The providers of the web analysis services may use the data collected to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network. SignUpGenius may utilize additional features of such web analytics services. Data that is collected may include: cookie data, usage data, geographic data, demographic data, and interest data. For more info on Google's privacy policies, visit the  [Google Privacy Center](http://www.google.com/privacy.html). Visitors can opt-out of Google Analytics for Display Advertising and customize Google Display Network ads using the  [Google's Ads Settings](https://www.google.com/settings/u/0/ads?hl=en). Google also offers an [opt-out browser add-on](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/).

**Third-Party Ad Networks**  
We partner with third-party ad networks. The use of cookies and/or web beacons to collect data is used in the ad serving process. SignUpGenius does not have access to this data. The third-party ad networks may use the DART cookie, which collects data when an ad is viewed or clicked on, to serve ads to our users based on their previous visits to our sites and other sites on the Internet. For ads utilizing the Google advertising system, users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie for interest-based advertising by visiting [Google's Ads Settings](https://adssettings.google.com/u/0/authenticated?hl=en). For further details on Google and their privacy policy, see the [Google Privacy Center](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en&gl=us).In addition, SignUpGenius allows other trusted third-party companies or vendors to collect certain non-personally identifiable information. Our partners may place or recognize a cookie on your computer, device, or directly in our emails/communications. These partners may utilize cookies, pixels or other technologies to collect and use non-personally identifiable information (e.g., hashed data, click stream information, browser type, time and date, subject of advertisements clicked or scrolled over, or other non-personally identifiable data) during your visits to this and other web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services likely to be of greater interest to you. To learn more about this behavioral advertising practice or to opt-out of this type of advertising, you can visit the websites of the Digital Advertising Alliance at [www.aboutads.info](http://www.aboutads.info/) and Networking Advertising Initiative at [www.networkadvertising.org/choices/](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/). 

For a summary of the kinds of cookies in use by SignUpGenius and its third party partner visit this Cookie Table.

Additionally, emails we send may contain a bit of code known as a "web beacon." This code allows us to understand the time and date of when a user has opened an email and when he/she has utilized a link within the email to visit a website. Our web beacons do not collect personally identifiable information and you may disable our web beacons. Please see your email client for more information regarding disabling web beacons.If you would like to request your SignUpGenius account data or deletion of your data, please click here. 

**California Do Not Track Disclosure**  
At this time SignUpGenius does not respond to browser “Do Not Track” signals.

Posted by Dan Rutledge
